Okay, so the first one that I've heard,
um, this is more common at the end of
last year, is that, you know, AI is
going to write 90 plus percent of the
code, you know, within a year.
Um, curious what you think on that.
>> Well, for certain classes of apps, that
that might be like all of I code coded
apps they're writing 100% of the code,
right? And and there's an awful lot of
that being written.
Are they going to write 90% of the high
quality code on the internet? I don't
know about that. Um, so
the the thing is like 90% of what? The
volume of written code is just like
going like that right now, right?
Because AI writes so much code.
>> [laughter]
>> So, so in a sense that's a
self-fulfilling prophecy, right?
>> [laughter]
>> But but but when it comes to like
the super high quality code that no one
has ever written before,
um, it's not clear to me that AI is
going to write 90% of that.
>> So, when you think about cases that AI
is not writing all the code, I mean,
maybe some examples of the super high
quality stuff. What is that?
>> [sighs]
>> Well,
I mean, it's it's algorithms that no one
has ever seen before, for example, or or
particular solutions like I mean, I I
know that AI could not write our
compiler, the TypeScript compiler. It it
just can't.
I mean, we've tried. It it it can't do
it. Um,
and I'm not asking it to, either. I
mean, I'm not expecting it to, either.
Um,
but
but our compiler is also not a typical
piece of code. I mean, that's why it's
bad at writing it, because it's seen
none of it in the training set. Well,
I've seen some compilers, but not like
this one, not with these concepts, not
with done the way that that we're doing
it, right? And so,
it's just not a good fit there. AI we we
we can't forget that AI is at heart a
big stochastic machine that has
memorized the entire internet, right?
And and his ability and has an ability
to extrapolate somewhat over what it's
memorized, right? Um but if it hasn't
seen it before, it's it's it's not
necessarily going to be all that good at
at doing it. Um it's getting to be
better. I mean, I'm not saying it's it's
not impressive. I did it's wildly
impressive what it can do.
But
I just think there's a long way still to
it doing all of it.
I don't and I don't know that we ever
get there. I hope we don't because then
what's the point of humans anymore then?
I mean, it's
>> [laughter]
>> What I see this take often too is
um you know,
you won't need to use an IDE within the
year or you don't need to read the code
anymore.
>> Well, good luck to you. I mean, if
you're going to hand AI the keys,
I mean, then all bets are off, right? I
mean, the minute AI you can't convince
AI to fix this issue or this new feature
that you want built,
>> what are you going to do?
>> I mean,
>> [laughter]
>> if you don't understand what what's
below, right?
There's a that's one problem. The other
problem is let's say a user comes to you
and goes, "Gee, your app just stole my
bank account. I'm
Well, it's going to sue you. It's not
they're going to sue you, not the AI. I
mean, it's like at the end of the day,
someone has to take responsibility for
what AI is doing.
And if you're giving it the keys, well,
it's on you.
You know, but but
I don't know.
>> [laughter]
>> I personally would not feel comfortable.
I wouldn't be able to go to sleep at
night. I mean, the if I didn't
understand what it is that I am vouching
for.
>> Why is there such a big difference
between this opinion and what I see from
maybe people who work at Anthropic?
>> Well, the difference is all I'm saying
here is not that AI can't do amazing
things. It does. It can. it does that
every day. But
but people love these like take it all
the way to 100%, right? And that's where
I get off the bus a little bit, right? I
think oh yeah, okay, fine. We can get we
can get higher and higher percentage.
But there still has to be someone
understanding what's going on and how
it's relevant to our business problem
and how it relates to what our
organization is doing and like and
there's so many other things that have
to be connected that it's I think it's
wrong to just view it as AI did it all
and we were completely unnecessary, you
know, and
>> Yeah, the next one I was going to ask
you was, you know, 3 years from now will
AI replace junior software engineers or
what junior software engineers do today?
>> Well, if it does then how do you ever
get senior software engineers?
Right? I mean it it's just like I don't
think so. Well, I'm not unless you also
believe that you will be able to do your
business
3 years later than that without any
senior software engineers.
>> Right.
>> Because where are they going to come
from?
You got to train them.
I mean and but to me
I think maybe one thing that to some
extent has happened is that for certain
classes of programmers the the the
pyramid has narrowed at the bottom,
right? There are fewer people coming in.
Um
and we are wanting them to advance
higher up faster.
Um
so that they can get to this more
supervisory role, right? I think the the
craft of being a software engineer is
definitely changing from your your
typing in lines of code
to you're having agents type in lines of
code and you are reviewing the work of
the agents, right? And so
so you do more reviewing, less typing.
Um and some people love that. You know,
I mean and and and and really are
fantastic at at that workflow, right?
But it's it's a change in nature of of
what what the job looks like as a
programmer and this tool
that you now have in a toolbox is having
that impact, right? But it is but a
tool.
And there are still programmers involved
in the in the process. That I firmly
believe.
>> Sounds like you enjoy typing out the
code. Would you be less happy if 5 years
from now
>> I I I I for for 40 50 years I have
enjoyed typing out code. Um
I'm actually there there
some and so I will continue to type
certain parts of the code, you know, but
there are other parts of the code that I
don't particularly care to type. I don't
care to type in tests and follow all the
rigor of the particular testing
framework. Heck no, if I can farm that
out to AI, happy me.
You know.
Um
I do think reviewing has always been
harder for me. It's harder for me to
like spend time on reviewing other
people's code than it is, you know,
writing the code.
But I also think that over time we will
we can make that process of reviewing
code much more ergonomic than it is
today, right? I mean, often today you
just get here's like the list of the
files that were changed and here are the
deltas. You figure it out. Right? I
mean, AI could help us more there by
explaining what the changes are and and
and whatever. And so I I think we're
going to get better. This is going to
get more interesting, but it will change
the nature of of the craft.